1:"$Sreact.fragment"
2:I[7555,[],""]
3:I[1295,[],""]
4:I[9742,["177","static/chunks/app/layout-7d8a5f63f536cdcf.js"],"Analytics"]
6:I[9665,[],"OutletBoundary"]
9:I[9665,[],"ViewportBoundary"]
b:I[9665,[],"MetadataBoundary"]
d:I[6614,[],""]
:HL["/dva-c02-quiz-app/_next/static/css/31d717072bdb6d85.css","style"]
:HL["/dva-c02-quiz-app/_next/static/css/14ea25f3945b7722.css","style"]
0:{"P":null,"b":"_vngiHLbu7MHbT5WeOEMF","p":"/dva-c02-quiz-app","c":["","quiz","aws-developer-4540356",""],"i":false,"f":[[["",{"children":["quiz",{"children":[["id","aws-developer-4540356","d"],{"children":["__PAGE__",{}]}]}]},"$undefined","$undefined",true],["",["$","$1","c",{"children":[[["$","link","0",{"rel":"stylesheet","href":"/dva-c02-quiz-app/_next/static/css/31d717072bdb6d85.css","precedence":"next","crossOrigin":"$undefined","nonce":"$undefined"}],["$","link","1",{"rel":"stylesheet","href":"/dva-c02-quiz-app/_next/static/css/14ea25f3945b7722.css","precedence":"next","crossOrigin":"$undefined","nonce":"$undefined"}]],["$","html",null,{"lang":"en","children":["$","body",null,{"className":"font-sans __variable_1f39b6 __variable_c20681","children":[["$","$L2",null,{"parallelRouterKey":"children","error":"$undefined","errorStyles":"$undefined","errorScripts":"$undefined","template":["$","$L3",null,{}],"templateStyles":"$undefined","templateScripts":"$undefined","notFound":[[["$","title",null,{"children":"404: This page could not be found."}],["$","div",null,{"style":{"fontFamily":"system-ui,\"Segoe UI\",Roboto,Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif,\"Apple Color Emoji\",\"Segoe UI Emoji\"","height":"100vh","textAlign":"center","display":"flex","flexDirection":"column","alignItems":"center","justifyContent":"center"},"children":["$","div",null,{"children":[["$","style",null,{"dangerouslySetInnerHTML":{"__html":"body{color:#000;background:#fff;margin:0}.next-error-h1{border-right:1px solid rgba(0,0,0,.3)}@media (prefers-color-scheme:dark){body{color:#fff;background:#000}.next-error-h1{border-right:1px solid rgba(255,255,255,.3)}}"}}],["$","h1",null,{"className":"next-error-h1","style":{"display":"inline-block","margin":"0 20px 0 0","padding":"0 23px 0 0","fontSize":24,"fontWeight":500,"verticalAlign":"top","lineHeight":"49px"},"children":404}],["$","div",null,{"style":{"display":"inline-block"},"children":["$","h2",null,{"style":{"fontSize":14,"fontWeight":400,"lineHeight":"49px","margin":0},"children":"This page could not be found."}]}]]}]}]],[]],"forbidden":"$undefined","unauthorized":"$undefined"}],["$","$L4",null,{}]]}]}]]}],{"children":["quiz",["$","$1","c",{"children":[null,["$","$L2",null,{"parallelRouterKey":"children","error":"$undefined","errorStyles":"$undefined","errorScripts":"$undefined","template":["$","$L3",null,{}],"templateStyles":"$undefined","templateScripts":"$undefined","notFound":"$undefined","forbidden":"$undefined","unauthorized":"$undefined"}]]}],{"children":[["id","aws-developer-4540356","d"],["$","$1","c",{"children":[null,["$","$L2",null,{"parallelRouterKey":"children","error":"$undefined","errorStyles":"$undefined","errorScripts":"$undefined","template":["$","$L3",null,{}],"templateStyles":"$undefined","templateScripts":"$undefined","notFound":"$undefined","forbidden":"$undefined","unauthorized":"$undefined"}]]}],{"children":["__PAGE__",["$","$1","c",{"children":["$L5","$undefined",null,["$","$L6",null,{"children":["$L7","$L8",null]}]]}],{},null,false]},null,false]},null,false]},null,false],["$","$1","h",{"children":[null,["$","$1","G6dG4RKGRid7I6Ziv5Aqj",{"children":[["$","$L9",null,{"children":"$La"}],null]}],["$","$Lb",null,{"children":"$Lc"}]]}],false]],"m":"$undefined","G":["$d","$undefined"],"s":false,"S":true}
e:I[1184,["261","static/chunks/261-2d9b76ccba401937.js","200","static/chunks/app/quiz/%5Bid%5D/page-d7cb26530e4508b3.js"],"default"]
5:["$","$Le",null,{"quiz":{"id":"aws-developer-4540356","title":"Practice Test #1 (AWS Certified Developer Associate - DVA-C02)","description":"Practice questions for AWS Developer Associate (DVA-C02) exam â€” covering core AWS services like SQS, Lambda, DynamoDB, and more.","questions":[{"question":"Your SQS consumer has failed to process a message and you realise it is taking a long time for the message to be read back by other applications. How can you decrease that time?","answers":[{"text":"decrease VisibilityTimeout","isCorrect":true},{"text":"disable LongPolling","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use a FIFO queue","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use a lower DelaySeconds","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Once a message is received by one of the distributed consumers, the message cannot be read again until the visibility timeout of that particular message expires. By setting an appropriate visibility timeout for the specific message, we can control how sooner or later the message is avaialble for processing by other applications. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSSimpleQueueService/latest/SQSDeveloperGuide/sqs-visibility-timeout.html"},{"question":"Your SQS consumer takes once in a while an unpredictable long time to process messages, which in turn result in duplicate processing of these messages as they go longer than their default VisibilityTimeout. How can you remedy the situation for the few problematic messages?","answers":[{"text":"Use ChangeMessageVisibility","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Use DeleteMessage","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Change the Visibilty Timeout","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use Long Polling","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Once a message is received by one of the distributed consumers, the message cannot be read again until the visibility timeout of that particular message expires. If the message is not processed within the visibility timeout, there are chances that the message will be received again by the distributed consumers leading to duplication in processing of message. By setting a sufficient visibility timeout for the specific message, we can ensure that the same message is not received again by the distributed consumers as the original consumer will delete the message once it has processed. The visibility timeout of the few problematic messages can be altered using ChangeMessageVisibility. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSSimpleQueueService/latest/APIReference/API_ChangeMessageVisibility.html"},{"question":"You have a CloudFormation template and it starts with:Transform: 'AWS::Serverless-2016-10-31' What does the Transform represent?","answers":[{"text":"It's a SAM template","isCorrect":true},{"text":"It's an intrinsic function","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It's a Lambda function definition","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"The AWS::Serverless transform is specifically used for transforming an entire template written in the AWS Serverless Application Model (AWS SAM) syntax into a compliant AWS CloudFormation template. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSCloudFormation/latest/UserGuide/transform-aws-serverless.html"},{"question":"You are currently storing 500 GB of data on your S3 bucket \"my-corp\". What's the maximum file size an S3 bucket can contain?","answers":[{"text":"5 TB","isCorrect":true},{"text":"1 TB","isCorrect":false},{"text":"infinite","isCorrect":false},{"text":"50 TB","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Individual Amazon S3 objects can range in size from a minimum of 0 bytes to a maximum of 5 terabytes. The largest object that can be uploaded in a single PUT is 5 gigabytes. Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/s3/faqs/"},{"question":"You are creating multiple users and assigning the same IAM policy to them as they perform the same role. What should you have done differently?","answers":[{"text":"Create a group, assign the policy to the group and the users to the group","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Never assign the same policy to two user","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use only one account shared by your users","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Let your users have admin rights","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"IAM Groups is an abstraction making the management of user groups easier. For instance we want to add a new policy to all the users in a group. Now instead of assigining the policy to each individual user, it can just be assigned once to the IAM Group. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/IAM/latest/UserGuide/id.html"},{"question":"You want a deployment tool which will also provision instances if they are needed. Which service should you use?","answers":[{"text":"Elastic Beanstalk","isCorrect":true},{"text":"CodeDeploy","isCorrect":false},{"text":"CodePipeline","isCorrect":false},{"text":"ECS Classic","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"AWS Elastic Beanstalk lets you manage all of the resources that run your application as environments where each environment runs only a single application version at a time.When an environment is being created, Elastic Beanstalk provisions all the required resources needed to run the application version. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/elasticbeanstalk/latest/dg/concepts.html"},{"question":"You would like to store user session in an in-memory store that has extremely low latency. What service should you use?","answers":[{"text":"ElastiCache","isCorrect":true},{"text":"RDS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"DynamoDB","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Parameter Store","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"ElastiCache is a managed service offering from AWS for in-memory data storages. RDS and DynamoDB offering store data on the disk which obviously has a much higher read latency than that of memory. Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/elasticache/"},{"question":"You have stored all your applications secrets in SSM parameter store and your audit team needs to get a report to understand who has been issuing API calls against SSM parameter store. What do you use?","answers":[{"text":"CloudTrail","isCorrect":true},{"text":"SSM Parameter Store List feature","isCorrect":false},{"text":"SSM Parameter Store Access Logs in CloudWatch Logs","isCorrect":false},{"text":"SSM Parameter Store Access Logs in S3","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"CloudTrail captures all API calls for Systems Manager as events, including calls from the Systems Manager console and from code calls to the Systems Manager APIs. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/systems-manager/latest/userguide/monitoring-cloudtrail-logs.html"},{"question":"Which pseudo parameter can you use to make your CloudFormation independent of the accounts they're running under?","answers":[{"text":"AWS::AccountId","isCorrect":true},{"text":"AWS::NoValue","isCorrect":false},{"text":"AWS::Region","isCorrect":false},{"text":"AWS::StackName","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"AWS::AccountId returns the AWS account ID of the account in which the stack is being created Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSCloudFormation/latest/UserGuide/pseudo-parameter-reference.html"},{"question":"You want to deploy an application that relies on RDS and ElastiCache for storing data and user session data respectively. You have chosen Elastic Beanstalk as the platform to deploy the platform. The requirements are that the RDS database must be able to be used across different environments and never lost, while ElastiCache can be safely deployed for each environment and lost if an environment is destroyed. Which configuration will allow you to achieve that? (select two)","answers":[{"text":"RDS database defined externally and referenced through environment variables","isCorrect":true},{"text":"ElastiCache defined in .ebextensions/","isCorrect":true},{"text":"RDS database defined in .ebextensions/","isCorrect":false},{"text":"ElastiCache database defined externally and referenced through environment variables","isCorrect":false},{"text":"ElastiCache bundled with the application source code","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Any resources created as part of your .ebextensions is part of your CloudFormation template and will get deleted if the environment is terminated. Resources that need to persist environments deletions must be created externally"},{"question":"You are looking to deploy applications a fleet of EC2 instances, with precise blue/green strategy. You want full control over the deployment steps and the possibility to add hooks. Which service should you use?","answers":[{"text":"CodeDeploy","isCorrect":true},{"text":"CodeBuild","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Elastic Beanstalk","isCorrect":false},{"text":"CodePipeline","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"AWS CodeDeploy is a deployment service that automates application deployments to Amazon EC2 instances, on-premises instances, or serverless Lambda functions.AWS CodeBuild is a fully managed continuous integration service that compiles source code, runs tests, and produces software packages that are ready to deploy. CodePipeline automates the build, test, and deploy phases of your release process every time there is a code change.AWS Elastic Beanstalk is an easy-to-use service for deploying and scaling web applications and services. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codedeploy/latest/userguide/welcome.html"},{"question":"One of your SQS message is consistently failing to be processed by consumers. It is breaking your applications and you would like to automatically store them somewhere for further debugging. What should you do?","answers":[{"text":"Implement a DLQ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Use DeleteMessage","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Reduce the VisibiltyTimeout","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Increase the VisibilityTimeout","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Amazon SQS supports dead-letter queues, which other queues (source queues) can target for messages that can't be processed (consumed) successfully. Dead-letter queues are useful for debugging your application or messaging system because they let you isolate problematic messages to determine why their processing doesn't succeed.  Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSSimpleQueueService/latest/SQSDeveloperGuide/sqs-dead-letter-queues.html"},{"question":"You want to mask some fields returned by your Lambda functions before going back to the clients, through the API Gateway. How can you achieve that?","answers":[{"text":"Use Mapping Templates","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Deploy an interceptor shell script","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use a stage variable","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use a Lambda custom interceptor","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"API Gateway lets you use mapping templates to map the payload from a method request to the corresponding integration request and from an integration response to the corresponding method response. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/apigateway/latest/developerguide/api-gateway-mapping-template-reference.html"},{"question":"What is the naming convention for files allowing you to control your Elastic Beanstalk settings?","answers":[{"text":".ebextensions/<mysettings>.config","isCorrect":true},{"text":".ebextensions_<mysettings></mysettings>.config","isCorrect":false},{"text":".config/<mysettings>.ebextensions","isCorrect":false},{"text":".config_<mysettings>.ebextensions","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"You can add AWS Elastic Beanstalk configuration files (.ebextensions) to your web application's source code to configure your environment and customize the AWS resources that it contains. Configuration files are YAML- or JSON-formatted documents with a .config file extension that you place in a folder named .ebextensions and deploy in your application source bundle. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/elasticbeanstalk/latest/dg/ebextensions.html"},{"question":"In order to retrieve the region ID of an EC2 instance created with CloudFormation, which function should you use?","answers":[{"text":"!GetAtt","isCorrect":true},{"text":"!Ref","isCorrect":false},{"text":"!Sub","isCorrect":false},{"text":"!FindInMap","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"The Fn::GetAtt intrinsic function returns the value of an attribute from a resource in the template. We can use the above function to get the regions ID attribute of the required EC2 instance by passing region ID as the attributeName and EC2 instance ID as logicalNameOfResource. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSCloudFormation/latest/UserGuide/intrinsic-function-reference-getatt.html"},{"question":"Your application needs to have an authentication mechanism that returns a JWT (JSON Web Token) after the user has identified. Which service validates the requirements?","answers":[{"text":"Cognito User Pools","isCorrect":true},{"text":"API Gateway","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Cognito Identity Pools","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Cognito Sync","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"After successfully authenticating a user, Amazon Cognito issues JSON web tokens (JWT) that you can use to secure and authorize access to your own APIs, or exchange for AWS credentials. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/cognito/latest/developerguide/amazon-cognito-user-pools-using-tokens-with-identity-providers.html"},{"question":"How many arguments does the CloudFormation !FindInMap function take?","answers":[{"text":"3","isCorrect":true},{"text":"2","isCorrect":false},{"text":"4","isCorrect":false},{"text":"1","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Following are the argumentsMapNameTopLevelKeySecondLevelKey Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSCloudFormation/latest/UserGuide/intrinsic-function-reference-findinmap.html"},{"question":"You know that your build time should not exceed 5 minutes for a particular application. Recently, some HTTP network was hung and CodeBuild was running for over an hour. How can you prevent that issue in the future?","answers":[{"text":"Enable CodeBuild timeouts","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Use AWS Lambda","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use AWS CloudWatch Events","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use VPC Flow Logs","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"By setting the timeout configuration, the build process will automatically terminate post the expiry of configured timeout.  Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codebuild/latest/userguide/change-project.html"},{"question":"What is the most simple way to run a CLI command against a region that hasn't been configured as the default?","answers":[{"text":"Use the --region parameter","isCorrect":true},{"text":"You need the override the default region use aws configure","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You should create a new profile just for that other region","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use boto3 dependency injection","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"If the region parameter is not set, then the CLI command is executed against the default AWS region. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/cli/latest/topic/config-vars.html#general-options"},{"question":"You would like to distribute your API to various customers and ensure their consumption is limited by the plans they have subscribed to. Which feature allows you to do that?","answers":[{"text":"Usage Plans & API Keys","isCorrect":true},{"text":"AWS Billing","isCorrect":false},{"text":"CloudTrail","isCorrect":false},{"text":"AWS Lambda Custom Authorizers","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"You can configure usage plans and API keys to allow customers to access selected APIs at agreed-upon request rates and quotas that meet their business requirements and budget constraints. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/apigateway/latest/developerguide/api-gateway-api-usage-plans.html"},{"question":"The company has a requirement to delete the data from CloudWatch Logs after 1 week for security compliance. Which feature will help you in achieving that?","answers":[{"text":"CloudWatch log expiration policies","isCorrect":true},{"text":"AWS Lambda with a CloudWatch Event","isCorrect":false},{"text":"CloudWatch S3 exporter","isCorrect":false},{"text":"CloudWatch Log Streams","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"By default, logs are kept indefinitely and never expire. You can adjust the retention policy for each log group, keeping the indefinite retention, or choosing a retention periods between 10 years and one day. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonCloudWatch/latest/logs/WhatIsCloudWatchLogs.html"},{"question":"You are looking to push Docker images into ECR with your AWS CodePipeline and CodeBuild. The last step fails with an authorization issue. What is the issue?","answers":[{"text":"Double check your IAM permissions for CodeBuild service","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Delete and re-create ECR repositories","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Open an AWS support ticket","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You first need to run an ECS instance","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"By default, IAM users don't have permission to create or modify Amazon ECR resources, or perform tasks using the Amazon ECR API. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonECR/latest/userguide/ECR_IAM_policies.html"},{"question":"You are building a movie database. Which attribute is the best partition key to maximize data distribution in DynamoDB?","answers":[{"text":"movie_id","isCorrect":true},{"text":"producer_name","isCorrect":false},{"text":"lead_actor_name","isCorrect":false},{"text":"movie_language","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"As the movie_id is unique in nature across the entire collection of movies database, hence it is the suitable candidate for the partition key in this usecase. Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/database/choosing-the-right-dynamodb-partition-key/"},{"question":"What service does Elastic Beanstalk rely on in order to deploy applications to AWS Cloud?","answers":[{"text":"CloudFormation","isCorrect":true},{"text":"CodeCommit","isCorrect":false},{"text":"AWS Lambda","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Systems Manager","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Beanstalk behind the scenes creates a cloudformation template. Have a try creating a new Beanstalk environment!"},{"question":"You would like to deploy a new application version without spending any incremental money while making sure the application does not experience any downtime. Which deployment mode fits your needs?","answers":[{"text":"rolling","isCorrect":true},{"text":"immutable","isCorrect":false},{"text":"all at once","isCorrect":false},{"text":"rolling with additional batches","isCorrect":false},{"text":"blue/green","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"All at once deployment policy causes downtime.All other deployment policies except rolling policy don't cause downtime but incur additional expenses. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/elasticbeanstalk/latest/dg/using-features.rolling-version-deploy.htmlhttps://docs.aws.amazon.com/elasticbeanstalk/latest/dg/using-features.deploy-existing-version.html"},{"question":"You need to dynamically obtain the instance-id of your EC2 instances from within your applications running on the EC2 instances. What's the easiest way to achieve it?","answers":[{"text":"Use EC2 meta data service","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Attach an IAM role and allow the ec2 describes-instances permission","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use EC2 User Data","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Inject that information using AWS Lambda","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"As your instance metadata is available from your running instance, you do not need to use the Amazon EC2 console or the AWS CLI. This can be helpful when you're writing scripts to run from your instance. For example, you can access the local IP address of your instance from instance metadata to manage a connection to an external application. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/ec2-instance-metadata.html#instancedata-data-retrieval"},{"question":"You are looking to automatically deploy AWS Lambda functions, with precise deployment rollout strategies. Which AWS service should you use?","answers":[{"text":"CodeDeploy","isCorrect":true},{"text":"CodeBuild","isCorrect":false},{"text":"CodeCommit","isCorrect":false},{"text":"CodePipeline","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"You can deploy a nearly unlimited variety of application content, such as code, serverless AWS Lambda functions, web and configuration files, executables, packages, scripts, multimedia files, and so on. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codedeploy/latest/userguide/welcome.html"},{"question":"Which of the following is not a valid CloudFormation section?","answers":[{"text":"Dependencies","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Resources","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Parameters","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Conditions","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Refer to the link under  Read more:  column for more detailed explaination. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSCloudFormation/latest/UserGuide/template-anatomy.html"},{"question":"You are trying to track API calls made in your AWS account for compliance purposes. Which service should you use?","answers":[{"text":"CloudTrail","isCorrect":true},{"text":"CloudWatch Metrics","isCorrect":false},{"text":"X-Ray","isCorrect":false},{"text":"CloudWatch Alarms","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"AWS CloudTrail is a service that enables governance, compliance, operational auditing, and risk auditing of your AWS account. With CloudTrail, you can log, continuously monitor, and retain account activity related to actions across your AWS infrastructure. Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/cloudtrail/"},{"question":"Which of the following is NOT an added resource type by Serverless Application Model?","answers":[{"text":"AWS::Serverless::UserPool","isCorrect":true},{"text":"AWS::Serverless::Function","isCorrect":false},{"text":"AWS::Serverless::Api","isCorrect":false},{"text":"AWS::Serverless::SimpleTable","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"AWS::Serverless::Function creates a Lambda function, IAM execution role, and event source mappings which trigger the function.AWS::Serverless::Api creates a collection of Amazon API Gateway resources and methods that can be invoked through HTTPS endpoints.The AWS::Serverless::SimpleTable resource creates a DynamoDB table with a single attribute primary key. Read more: https://github.com/awslabs/serverless-application-model/blob/master/versions/2016-10-31.md#format"},{"question":"You would like to implement a 3rd party authentication for your AWS API Gateway. Which authorizer do you choose?","answers":[{"text":"Lambda Authorizer","isCorrect":true},{"text":"IAM permissions with sigv4","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Cognito User Pools","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"An Amazon API Gateway Lambda authorizer is a Lambda function that you provide to control access to your API methods. A Lambda authorizer uses bearer token authentication strategies, such as OAuth or SAML. It can also use information described by headers, paths, query strings, stage variables, or context variables request parameters. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/apigateway/latest/developerguide/apigateway-use-lambda-authorizer.html"},{"question":"You have a requirement to leverage a NoSQL hosted database in the AWS Cloud, that can auto scale. Which database would you choose?","answers":[{"text":"DynamoDB","isCorrect":true},{"text":"RDS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Redshift","isCorrect":false},{"text":"ElastiCache","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Amazon DynamoDB is a nonrelational database that delivers reliable performance at any scale. It's a fully managed, multi-region, multi-master database that provides consistent single-digit millisecond latency.RDS is managed service for RDBMS, Redshift is a petabyte scale warehouse service and ElastCache is an in-memory storage service. Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/dynamodb/"},{"question":"Your Elastic Beanstalk application must encrypt payloads of up to 10MB. Which method will help you achieve that?","answers":[{"text":"Use the Encryption SDK","isCorrect":true},{"text":"KMS Encrypt API Call","isCorrect":false},{"text":"S3 Encrypt API Call","isCorrect":false},{"text":"IAM Encrypt API call","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"The AWS Encryption SDK is an encryption library that helps make it easier for you to implement encryption best practices in your application.  Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/encryption-sdk/latest/developer-guide/introduction.html"},{"question":"In order to pass artifacts between various stages, which AWS Service is leveraged by CodePipeline?","answers":[{"text":"S3","isCorrect":true},{"text":"SQS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"AWS Lambda","isCorrect":false},{"text":"EFS","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"The Artifact Store is an Amazon S3 bucket that CodePipeline uses to store artifacts used by pipelines. When you first use the CodePipeline console in a region to create a pipeline, CodePipeline automatically generates this S3 bucket in the AWS region. It stores artifacts for all pipelines in that region in this bucket. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codepipeline/latest/userguide/S3-artifact-encryption.html"},{"question":"Your API Gateway is enabled to send access logs to CloudWatch but it seems that CloudWatch isn't receiving any data. What is the likely root cause of this issue?","answers":[{"text":"Check the Service IAM permissions","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Check the CloudWatch Logs Policy","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Also enable X-Ray integration","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Ensure in-flight encryption is disabled","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"To enable CloudWatch Logs, you must grant API Gateway permission to read and write logs to CloudWatch for your account. The AmazonAPIGatewayPushToCloudWatchLogs managed policy (with an ARN of arn:aws:iam::aws:policy/service-role/AmazonAPIGatewayPushToCloudWatchLogs) has all the required permissions Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/apigateway/latest/developerguide/set-up-logging.html"},{"question":"You have a fleet of 100 000 trucks that continuously send data to your cloud. This big data stream must be delivered to multiple consuming applications. This solution must be able to scale as the load increases. Which technology is the most suitable?","answers":[{"text":"Kinesis Stream","isCorrect":true},{"text":"SNS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"SQS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Lambda","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Kinesis data streams can continuously capture gigabytes of data per second from hundreds of thousands of sources such as website clickstreams, database event streams, financial transactions, social media feeds, IT logs, and location-tracking events.  Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/kinesis/data-streams/"},{"question":"CodePipeline fails with an authorisation issue. What is the best way to determine the root cause of the problem?","answers":[{"text":"Check the Service IAM permissions","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Check changes in CloudTrail","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Check the recent changes in CloudWatch","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Audit the S3 bucket CORS policy where the artifacts are stored","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Any authorization related failure directly indicates to us that our first point of debugging should be validating the IAM permissions for the service. Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/cloudtrail/https://docs.aws.amazon.com/IAM/latest/UserGuide/access_policies_testing-policies.html"},{"question":"Which of the following integration technology pushes data to consumers?","answers":[{"text":"SNS","isCorrect":true},{"text":"SQS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Kinesis","isCorrect":false},{"text":"SES","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"SNS pushes while others pull"},{"question":"Your client is asking how KMS Encryption works. You explain that  ","answers":[{"text":"KMS stores the CMK, and receives data from the clients, which it encrypts and sends back.","isCorrect":true},{"text":"KMS receives CMK from the client at every Encrypt call, and encrypts the data with that","isCorrect":false},{"text":"KMS sends the CMK to the client, which performs the encryption and then deletes the CMK","isCorrect":false},{"text":"KMS generates a new CMK for each Encrypt call and encrypts the data with it","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Refer to the link under  Read more:  column for more detailed explaination. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/kms/latest/developerguide/concepts.html"},{"question":"You have requested credentials using STS when your applications boots. After an hour, your application stops working and needs to be manually restarted to work again. What is happening?","answers":[{"text":"Your application needs to renew the credentials after 1 hour when they expire","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Your IAM policy is wrong","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A lambda function revokes your access every hour","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The IAM service is experiencing downtime once an hour","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Credentials that are created by using account credentials can range from 900 seconds (15 minutes) up to a maximum of 3,600 seconds (1 hour), with a default of 1 hour. Hence you need to renew the credentials post expiry. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/STS/latest/APIReference/API_GetSessionToken.html"},{"question":"Which protocol is not supported by CloudFront?","answers":[{"text":"UDP","isCorrect":true},{"text":"HTTP","isCorrect":false},{"text":"HTTPS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"RTMP","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":" Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonCloudFront/latest/DeveloperGuide/distribution-overview.html"},{"question":"Which following two terms belong to the SNS product? (select two)","answers":[{"text":"topic","isCorrect":true},{"text":"subscription","isCorrect":true},{"text":"queue","isCorrect":false},{"text":"consumer","isCorrect":false},{"text":"retention","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Using Amazon SNS topics, your publisher systems can fan out messages to a large number of subscriber endpoints for parallel processing Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/sns/"},{"question":"You have deployed a Java application on EC2 and made sure to enable the X-Ray SDK. The application was sending data to X-Ray when you tested it from your personal computer. The deployed application fails to send data to X-Ray. Which of the following component debugging won't help resolve the problem?","answers":[{"text":"X-Ray sampling","isCorrect":true},{"text":"EC2 X-Ray agent","isCorrect":false},{"text":"EC2 Instance Role","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Security Groups Rules","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"The X-Ray SDK applies a sampling algorithm to efficiently trace and provide a representative sample of the requests that your application serves. This can be utilised post the data is being successfully being sent to X-Ray and in no way helps us in determining the cause of failure to send the data to X-Ray. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/xray/latest/devguide/xray-concepts.html#xray-concepts-sampling"},{"question":"You want to provision your own Docker images that can be used as an input for CodeBuild. These images will contain cached dependencies as well as special tooling for your builds that are proprietary to your company. Where should you push these images?","answers":[{"text":"ECR","isCorrect":true},{"text":"S3","isCorrect":false},{"text":"EFS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"EBS","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Amazon Elastic Container Registry (ECR) is a fully-managed Docker container registry that makes it easy for developers to store, manage, and deploy Docker container images. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codebuild/latest/userguide/sample-ecr.html"},{"question":"Your CodeBuild has failed and you would like to perform some hands-on debugging. How should you proceed?","answers":[{"text":"Run AWS CodeBuild locally","isCorrect":true},{"text":"SSH into the CodeBuild Docker container","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Freeze the CodeBuild during its next execution","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Enable detailed monitoring","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"With the Local Build support for AWS CodeBuild, now you just specify the location of your source code, choose your build settings, and CodeBuild runs build scripts for compiling, testing, and packaging your code. Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/devops/announcing-local-build-support-for-aws-codebuild/"},{"question":"You are looking to run the same application multiple times on your EC2 instance and expose it with a load balancer. You should use","answers":[{"text":"Application Load Balancer + ECS","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Classic Load Balancer + ECS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Application Load Balancer + Beanstalk","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Classic Load Balancer + Beanstalk","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Application Load Balancers allow containers to use dynamic host port mapping (so that multiple tasks from the same service are allowed per container instance). Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonECS/latest/developerguide/service-load-balancing.html"},{"question":"Someone just deleted an EC2 instance. Which AWS Service will allow you to find out who did it?","answers":[{"text":"CloudTrail","isCorrect":true},{"text":"EC2 Logs","isCorrect":false},{"text":"CloudWatch","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Config","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"AWS CloudTrail is a service that enables governance, compliance, operational auditing, and risk auditing of your AWS account. With CloudTrail, you can log, continuously monitor, and retain account activity related to actions across your AWS infrastructure. Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/cloudtrail/"},{"question":"Which section in mandatory in CloudFormation templates?","answers":[{"text":"Resources","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Parameters","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Outputs","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Mappings","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Resources is the only mandatory section of the CloudFormation template and rest all sections are optional. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSCloudFormation/latest/UserGuide/template-anatomy.html"},{"question":"You want to give a temporary read access to your S3 files. How can you do this ?","answers":[{"text":"Using pre-signed URL","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Using bucket policy","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Using Routing Policy","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Not possible","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"All objects by default are private. Only the object owner has permission to access these objects. However, the object owner can optionally share objects with others by creating a presigned URL, using their own security credentials, to grant time-limited permission to download the objects. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/ShareObjectPreSignedURL.html"},{"question":"In DynamoDB, what's the maximum number of attributes that can be combined to form a primary key?","answers":[{"text":"2","isCorrect":true},{"text":"1","isCorrect":false},{"text":"3","isCorrect":false},{"text":"4","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"The primary key can just consist of a simple partition key as a single attribute or a max of two attributes as a composite key consisting of partition key and sort key. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazondynamodb/latest/developerguide/HowItWorks.CoreComponents.html#HowItWorks.CoreComponents.PrimaryKey"},{"question":"An application is hosted by a 3rd party and is exposed as yourapp.3rdparty.com. You would like to have your users access your application using mydomain.com , which you own and manage under Route53. What record should you create?","answers":[{"text":"Create a CNAME record","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Create an A record","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Create a PTR record","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Create an Alias Record","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"CNAME records can be used to alias one name to another. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/Route53/latest/DeveloperGuide/ResourceRecordTypes.html#CNAMEFormat"},{"question":"Your business model requires that your website will be visited daily from 8am to 11pm except weekends.What is the best EC2 payment plan while reducing the cost of hosting ?","answers":[{"text":"Scheduled Instances","isCorrect":true},{"text":"On-demand Instances","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Classic Instances","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Spot Instances","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Scheduled instances allow you to reserve capacity on a recurring basis with a daily, weekly, or monthly schedule over the course of a one-year term. Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/new-scheduled-reserved-instances/"},{"question":"You would like to have a secured and versioned way of storing your database credentials. Which service do you pick?","answers":[{"text":"SSM Parameter Store","isCorrect":true},{"text":"EFS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"EBS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"KMS","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"AWS Systems Manager Parameter Store provides secure, hierarchical storage for configuration data management and secrets management. You can store data such as passwords, database strings, and license codes as parameter values. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/systems-manager/latest/userguide/systems-manager-paramstore.html"},{"question":"Your client is migrating an application to the cloud and needs a technology to ensure your application can be stateless and store data in a low latency in memory store. What do you recommend?","answers":[{"text":"ElastiCache","isCorrect":true},{"text":"RDS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"DynamoDB","isCorrect":false},{"text":"S3","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"ElastiCache is a managed service offering from AWS for in-memory data storages. Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/elasticache/"},{"question":"You want to route traffic based on the location of your resources and, optionally, shift traffic from resources in one location to resources in another. Which routing policy is suitable for your case ?","answers":[{"text":"Geoproximity","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Geolocation","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Failover","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Latency","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Weighted","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Simple routing policy   : Use for a single resource that performs a given function for your domain.Failover routing policy   : Use when you want to configure active-passive failover.Geolocation routing policy   : Use when you want to route traffic based on the location of your users.Geoproximity routing policy   : Use when you want to route traffic based on the location of your resources and, optionally, shift traffic from resources in one location to resources in another.Latency routing policy   : Use when you have resources in multiple AWS Regions and you want to route traffic to the region that provides the best latency.Multivalue answer routing policy   : Use when you want Route 53 to respond to DNS queries with up to eight healthy records selected at random.Weighted routing policy   : Use to route traffic to multiple resources in proportions that you specify. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/Route53/latest/DeveloperGuide/routing-policy.html"},{"question":"CodeBuild fails as it cannot pull a Docker image stored in ECR. What is the most likely reason?","answers":[{"text":"Missing IAM permissions for the CodeBuild Service","isCorrect":true},{"text":"The Docker image is missing some tags","isCorrect":false},{"text":"CodeBuild cannot work with custom Docker images","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The Docker image is too big","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"By default, IAM users don't have permission to create or modify Amazon ECR resources, or perform tasks using the Amazon ECR API. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonECR/latest/userguide/ECR_IAM_policies.html"},{"question":"What can't CloudFormation Conditions be applied to?","answers":[{"text":"Parameters","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Resources","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Conditions","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Outputs","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"You can create a condition and then associate it with a resource or output so that AWS CloudFormation only creates the resource or output if the condition is true. Optionally within each condition, you can reference another condition as well. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSCloudFormation/latest/UserGuide/conditions-section-structure.html"},{"question":"You would like to query items based on an attribute that is not part of the DynamoDB partition key. What should you do?","answers":[{"text":"Create a GSI","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Call Scan","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Create a LSI","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Migrate away from DynamoDB","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Some applications might need to perform many kinds of queries, using a variety of different attributes other than the specified partition key as query criteria. To support these requirements, you can create one or more global secondary indexes and issue Query requests against these indexes. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazondynamodb/latest/developerguide/GSI.html"},{"question":"What are SNS messages sent to?","answers":[{"text":"topic","isCorrect":true},{"text":"queue","isCorrect":false},{"text":"stream","isCorrect":false},{"text":"forum","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Using Amazon SNS topics, your publisher systems can fan out messages to a large number of subscriber endpoints for parallel processing Read more: https://aws.amazon.com/sns/"},{"question":"Which of the following isn't a supported mechanism of authentication for API Gateway?","answers":[{"text":"STS","isCorrect":true},{"text":"IAM permissions with sigv4","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Lambda Authorizer","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Cognito User Pools","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Following mechanisms are supported by the API Gateways for authentication Resource policiesStandard AWS IAM roles and policiesCross-origin resource sharing (CORS)Lambda authorizersAmazon CognitoClient-side SSL certificatesUsage plans Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/apigateway/latest/developerguide/apigateway-control-access-to-api.html"},{"question":"Should non exported CloudFormation outputs must a region-level unique name?","answers":[{"text":"no","isCorrect":true},{"text":"yes","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Only the exported CloudFormation, Export names must be unique within a region for each AWS account. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSCloudFormation/latest/UserGuide/outputs-section-structure.html"},{"question":"You have created a target group which has marked all your EC2 instances as unhealthy. Surprisingly, when you directly enter the IP of the EC2 instances in your web browser, you are able to access your website. So you know it is running, but what could be the reason of your instances being marked as unhealthy? (select two)","answers":[{"text":"The security group of the EC2 instance does not allow for traffic from the security group of the Application Load Balancer","isCorrect":true},{"text":"The route for the health check is misconfigured","isCorrect":true},{"text":"The EBS volumes have been unproperly mounted","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Your web-app has a runtime that is not supported by the Application Load Balancer","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You need to attach Elastic IP to the EC2 instances","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"You must ensure that your load balancer can communicate with registered targets on both the listener port and the health check port. Whenever you add a listener to your load balancer or update the health check port for a target group used by the load balancer to route requests, you must verify that the security groups associated with the load balancer allow traffic on the new port in both directions. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/elasticloadbalancing/latest/network/target-group-health-checks.htmlhttps://docs.aws.amazon.com/elasticloadbalancing/latest/application/load-balancer-update-security-groups.html"},{"question":"Which language is not supported by CloudFormation?","answers":[{"text":"Python","isCorrect":true},{"text":"YAML","isCorrect":false},{"text":"JSON","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"A CloudFormation template is stored as a text file whose format complies with the JavaScript Object Notation (JSON) or YAML standard. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSCloudFormation/latest/UserGuide/gettingstarted.templatebasics.html"},{"question":"You would like to deploy a new application version using Beanstalk but don't want to bring your capacity down. You are also very cost conscious and want to ensure any added cost will be minimal. Which deployment fits your needs?","answers":[{"text":"rolling with additional batches","isCorrect":true},{"text":"immutable","isCorrect":false},{"text":"all at once","isCorrect":false},{"text":"rolling","isCorrect":false},{"text":"blue/green","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Rolling with additonal batches is the most optimum deployment policy when a user doesn't want to compromise on the output capacity of the application but also keep the additional expense incurs to the minimum.Rolling with additional batch   : Deploy the new version in batches, but first launch a new batch of instances to ensure full capacity during the deployment process. Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/elasticbeanstalk/latest/dg/using-features.rolling-version-deploy.htmlhttps://docs.aws.amazon.com/elasticbeanstalk/latest/dg/using-features.deploy-existing-version.html"},{"question":"You have a Pipeline in AWS CodePipeline that contains a lot of steps. Some steps need to be ordered while other can run simultaneously. You would like to speed up your CodePipeline. How do you achieve it?","answers":[{"text":"Re-design the pipeline to include steps to occur in parallel where possible","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Upgrade the AWS CodePipeline instance type","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Ask for a \"speed boost\" from the AWS support","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Enable pipeline caching","isCorrect":false}],"explanation":"Actions in parallel in CodePipeline can help with speed requirements Read more: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codepipeline/latest/userguide/reference-pipeline-structure.html#action-requirements"}]}}]
a:[["$","meta","0",{"charSet":"utf-8"}],["$","meta","1",{"name":"viewport","content":"width=device-width, initial-scale=1"}]]
7:null
8:null
c:[["$","title","0",{"children":"v0 App"}],["$","meta","1",{"name":"description","content":"Created with v0"}],["$","meta","2",{"name":"generator","content":"v0.app"}]]
